In heroes we trust.
Captain America: The Winter Soldier is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Joe Russo.
After the cataclysmic events in New York with The Avengers, Steve Rogers,
aka Captain America is living quietly in Washington, D.C.
and trying to adjust to the modern world.
But when a S.H.I.E.L.D.
colleague comes under attack, Steve becomes embroiled in a web of
intrigue that threatens to put the world at risk.
Joining forces with the Black Widow, Captain America struggles to expose the ever-widening
conspiracy while fighting off professional assassins sent to silence him at every turn.
When the full scope of the villainous plot is revealed, Captain America and
the Black Widow enlist the help of a new ally, the Falcon.
However, they soon find themselves up against an unexpected
and formidable enemy—the Winter Soldier.
Steve Rogers / Captain America, played by Chris Evans.
Nick Fury, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Natasha Romanoff / Black Widow, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Alexander Pierce, played by Robert Redford.
Bucky Barnes / Winter Soldier, played by Sebastian Stan.
Sam Wilson / Falcon, played by Anthony Mackie.
Captain America: The Winter Soldier is a 2014 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character
Captain America, produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It is the sequel to Captain America: The First Avenger (2011) and the
ninth film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Anthony and Joe Russo from a
screenplay by Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely.
It stars Chris Evans as Steve Rogers / Captain America alongside Scarlett Johansson, Sebastian Stan, Anthony Mackie, Cobie
Smulders, Frank Grillo, Emily VanCamp, Hayley Atwell, Toby Jones, Jenny Agutter, Robert Redford, and Samuel L.
In the film, Rogers, Natasha Romanoff (Johansson), and Sam Wilson (Mackie)
uncover a conspiracy within the spy agency S.H.I.E.L.D.
while facing the Winter Soldier (Stan), a mysterious assassin.
Markus and McFeely began writing the sequel around the
release of The First Avenger in July 2011.
The script draws from the Winter Soldier story arc in the comic books written by Ed Brubaker, as well
as conspiracy fiction from the 1970s such as the film Three Days of the Condor (1975).
The Winter Soldier explores S.H.I.E.L.D.
in a similar way to how the first film explored the U.S.
military, after Rogers was shown working for S.H.I.E.L.D.
in the MCU crossover film The Avengers (2012).
The Russo brothers signed on to direct in June 2012
and casting began the following month.
They wanted the film to be a political thriller that focused on topical ideas
such as drone warfare, targeted killing, and global surveillance.
Filming began in April 2013 in Los Angeles, California, before
moving to Washington, D.C., and Cleveland, Ohio.
Though the directors prioritized practical effects and intense stunt work to differentiate from previous Captain America
portrayals, visual effects were created by six companies for 2,500 shots including the climactic Helicarrier sequence.
Captain America: The Winter Soldier premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on March
13, 2014, and was released in the United States on April 4, as part of Phase Two of the MCU.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for the
performances, action sequences, storyline, and themes.
It grossed $714 million worldwide, making it the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2014, and received
several accolades including a nomination for best visual effects at the 87th Academy Awards.
A sequel titled Captain America: Civil War, also
directed by the Russos, was released in 2016.
The film explores themes of washington dc, usa, superhero, based on
comic, aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is thought_provoking.